<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zhengjian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is a customized copyright.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 10:37:42 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://zhengjian-l.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Extension and Rebuttal</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/bp-debate/extension-and-rebuttal/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 10:37:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/bp-debate/extension-and-rebuttal/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/bp-debate/extension-and-rebuttal/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;extension&#34;&gt;Extension&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-extension&#34;&gt;What is an extension?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extension is a new contribution of material put forward by closing teams that aims to be the most &lt;strong&gt;important material&lt;/strong&gt; in the context of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extension can be radically new piece of material, or it can take an existing piece of material and developed further. It is basically anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can run multiple points of extension, and these points can be new substantive or new rebuttal (in the same way a second speaker might make a piece of rebuttal into a new pint of substantive).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an extension is indistinct from material brought by an opening team, the extension is considered &amp;ldquo;derivative&amp;rdquo; and is unlikely to be debate-winning. Make sure you emphasis what is new/different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-an-extension&#34;&gt;Tips for an extension&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally aim to do one of two things
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New argument to shift the focus of the debate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An argument that aims to decisively win the existing clash of the debate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to come up with extensions?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new argument (new stakeholders/contexts/areas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flip the opening argument(if they said what&amp;rsquo;s great about something push what happens if this motion doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deeper analysis of opening&amp;rsquo;s arguments (make sure this is clearly new and highlight the importance of the contributions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New rebuttal (should be framed as a key argument that disproves key parts of the opposition case)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tactics-for-an-extensionargument&#34;&gt;Tactics for an extension/argument&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stakeholder-impact-analysis&#34;&gt;Stakeholder Impact Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This house would make all schools co-educational(男女混校).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;School students&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;They would all have to attend co-educational schools.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parents&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;They would no longer have the choice of sending their children to single-sex schools.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teachers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Those who had only worked in single-sex schools (or preferred working in single-sex schools) would have to learn the different skills required for teaching both boys and girls.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The government&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Changing single-sex schools to mixed schools would take up a great deal of the Department for Education’s time and money.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Employers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eventually, everyone in the country would have attended a co-educational school. Would this make them better or worse at their jobs?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tips: The ranking on stakeholders matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ranking 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ranking 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ranking 3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Students&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Employers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parents&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parents&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The government&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teachers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Government&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teachers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Students&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Teachers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parents&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Employers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Employers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;School students&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Government&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranking 1: This order aim on how the impact on students personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranking 2: This suggests a world in which children&amp;rsquo;s needs are seen as less important than the needs of society as a whole. The purpose of education in this order of priorities is to fit children for the world of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranking 3: This ranking implies a &lt;strong&gt;libertarian&lt;/strong&gt; approach. Libertarianism means maximizing people’s freedom of choice. If parents are the most important people when it comes to their children’s education, they should be allowed to choose how their children are educated; it is not the government’s business to tell them what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;society-structure-analysis&#34;&gt;Society Structure Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;middle-class-theory&#34;&gt;Middle-Class Theory&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle-Class Theory suggests that we should classify most of the stakeholders into three categories (top, middle, and bottom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two characteristics of the middle class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing to the other two groups of people, they are more likely to change their behaviors or mentality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing to the other two groups of people, they are more likely to contribute to movements or social changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THW tax on junk food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top: people who love junk food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle(majority): people who neither love nor hate junk food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom: people who hate junk food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we tax on junk food, people in the middle class (who are the majority) would  consume junk food less. Totally, people are more healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pyramid-shaped-structure&#34;&gt;Pyramid-Shaped Structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a pyramid-shaped structure, we should classify most of the stakeholders into two categories(top and bottom). And the bottom is the majority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two characteristics of the bottom class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These people are the base of the society, concerning to the social steady.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are more conservative and traditional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THW legalize LGBTQ+ immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;theories-of-change&#34;&gt;Theories of Change&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A theory of change is a model (or strategy) that tries to predict how social and cultural change will be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of theories of change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structured change - which is when a political or legal structure is imposed on society to force certain changes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E.g. redistribution of wealth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic change - which is when underlying social forces lead to changing norms and values without government intervention.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E.g. intergenerational change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;extreme-organic-social-change&#34;&gt;Extreme Organic Social Change&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually used by opposition teams wanting to show that a government&amp;rsquo;s model of structured change is &lt;em&gt;unnecessary&lt;/em&gt;, (because change will happen anyway), and harmful (because organic change causes less backlash).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most extreme versions of the argument are teleological-which means that broad historical forces are driving social progress and can&amp;rsquo;t be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;less-extreme-organic-social-change&#34;&gt;Less Extreme Organic Social Change&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are less extreme versions of organic social change which focus on the need to actively change minds and attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these versions, change is not inevitable, but it&amp;rsquo;s also not dependent on government leadership - you need to change the community&amp;rsquo;s attitudes first, and then the politicians will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to achieve broad social change (e.g. ending patriarchy or racism) then you need a mass movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each mass movement is different, but they face common challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success breeds fragmentation of priorities (some of the former ‘out group’
move into the ‘in group’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backlashes (every action has an equal and opposite sub-reddit)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining the rage (first they ignore you, then they laugh at you, then they
celebrate your diversity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appealing to allies helps and hurts the movement (the price of being
‘respectable’ is being less radical).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;top-down-vs-bottom-up-strategies&#34;&gt;Top Down vs Bottom Up Strategies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a spectrum of strategies for achieving change that span bottom-up
approaches, through to top down methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom-up is the ‘mass model’ of change. It’s focused on building up a level of
public support that is politically irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top-down is the ‘elite model’ of change. It tries to convince decision makers
(politicians/CEOs, etc) to ‘do the right thing’ even if it is unpopular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each strategy has value and can be successful in the right context, and its
impossible to know for sure which approach will work ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real world campaigns for change often use a combination of strategies, but
debates (especially ‘actor’ topics) force you to defend what the tactics should
be of specific groups, and to understand how that group’s strategy will interact
with other groups pursuing different strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;four-types-of-tactics&#34;&gt;Four Types of Tactics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness raising and advocacy&lt;/strong&gt; (winning hearts and minds, shifting social norms, socializing new solutions and ways of thinking).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-led prevention of new harms&lt;/strong&gt; (taking action that lessens the problem immediately – e.g. donating to homeless shelter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal intervention against existing harms&lt;/strong&gt; (‘lawfare’ – using the courts to
block/reverse decisions that would make things worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parliamentary power&lt;/strong&gt; (trying to change who elected to help make better laws)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals-analysis&#34;&gt;Goals Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, debating is decision making. Of the elements of the decision-making process , perhaps the most significant was the goal; the goals we seek define the decisions we make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;discerning-goals&#34;&gt;Discerning Goals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primary goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ancillary goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;countering-arguments-with-goal-analysis&#34;&gt;Countering Arguments with Goal Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have identified the primary goal, you can use that goal to
demonstrate that your opponents’ proposal is undesirable. Typically,
you can use five approaches—employed alone or in concert with one
another—to prove this point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation.&lt;/strong&gt; Mitigation seeks to demonstrate that the proposal won’t accomplish the goal or won’t accomplish the goal in a significant way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contravention.&lt;/strong&gt; Arguing that a proposal may not be as effective as your opponents claim (mitigation) is not as powerful as arguing that your opponents’ proposal will actually move them farther from their goal. As an approach, contravention seeks to demonstrate that not only do things not get better but they actually get worse with the Proposition’s proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consequences.&lt;/strong&gt; All proposals have effects. Proponents of such proposals claim that those effects meet the goals they pursue. Opponents may gain ground by arguing that regardless of whether the primary goal sought by their opponents is met, the consequences of enacting the proposed policy render that policy undesirable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternative proposal.&lt;/strong&gt; Once you have demonstrated the undesirability of your opponents’ proposal, a powerful option is to offer an alternative proposal that will better meet their goal. To propose an alternative, you must first establish that your opponents’ proposal is undesirable either because it will not achieve the goal or because of the consequences of enacting the proposal. In either (or both) cases, you are creating the desire for an alternative in the minds of your adjudicators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternative goal.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, you have the option of arguing that your opponents’ goal is inappropriate (or at least should not be the primary goal). In my opinion, this approach is the least effective use of goal analysis. Nothing is more compelling than conceding the worth of your opponents’ goal and then demonstrating that they don’t achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rebuttal&#34;&gt;Rebuttal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In essence, rebuttal is about telling the other teams that they’re wrong, and that you’re right.&lt;/strong&gt; The problem is that quite often speakers will settle for rebuttal that is “non-comparative” – that is, it explains why something is bad or wrong, without explaining why the reverse might be true or why the world is better on their side. So, we’re going to quickly go through the anatomy of effective rebuttal that takes down the arguments of the other teams whilst bolstering your own position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;structuring-rebuttal&#34;&gt;Structuring Rebuttal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conventional way of structuring rebuttal into your speech is to put it at the beginning, after your headlines. You might start your speech by outlining the points you’re going to make, and then moving on to extraneous rebuttal. You might structure this by saying “Proposition said this [argument that Proposition made]. Our response is [PEE-formatted response that deals with the core of the argument]”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can interweave your rebuttal. This is where you make your substantive points clash directly with those of your opponents, and ideally flag those clashes up as you go along. You still need to explain why what you’re saying is either more true or more important than what the other team said, but it can save time or make your speech more fluent to not have to add in extraneous parts at the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely tempting to make your opponents’ arguments look worse than they actually are. This is called a “strawman”, and it’s generally considered bad practice. Not only is it a little intellectually dishonest, but unless you’re very good at it then it’s likely to get noticed by the judges. If you’re attacking a strawman of an opponent’s argument, then your rebuttal is less likely to be effective because it won’t deal with the core of the argument. Moreover, you leave yourself open to a speaker coming up after you and rebuilding the argument in a stronger way which you haven’t dealt with, overcoming your attempt at rebuttal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better strategy is to ensure that you take your opponents’ claims at their best. This means that if they haven’t made an argument particularly well, you should still try and pretend that they did and deal with that version of the argument.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/bp-debate/extension-and-rebuttal/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note|Free to Choose</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/5-free-to-choose/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:39:37 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/5-free-to-choose/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/5-free-to-choose/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;challenge-to-j-s-mills-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;Challenge to J. S. Mill&amp;rsquo;s Utilitarianism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is justice the chief part and the most binding part of our morality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it the only reason to respect other people&amp;rsquo;s rights that respecting people&amp;rsquo;s rights is a way of making everybody better off in the long run?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;libertarianism&#34;&gt;Libertarianism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fundamental idea:&lt;/strong&gt; Individuals matter not just as instruments to be used for a larger social purpose or for the sake of maximizing utility, individuals are separate beings with separate lives worthy of respect. We&amp;rsquo;re not available to any use that the society might desire or devise precisely because we are individual separate human beings. We have a fundamental right to liberty, and that means a right to choose freely, to live our lives as we please provided we respect other people&amp;rsquo;s rights to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Individuals have rights, and there are things no person or group may do to them (without violating their rights).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Robert Nozick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-libertarian-view-of-government&#34;&gt;The Libertarian View of Government&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No paternalist Legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laws that protect people from themselves, like seatbelt laws, should not exist. The libertarian thinks what people do should be up to them and it is coercion to forbid their behaviours by laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Morals Legislation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many laws try to promote the virtue of citizens or try to give expression to the moral values of the society as a whole. Libertarian say that&amp;rsquo;s also a violation of the right to liberty.
Example: Laws that prevent sexual intimacy between gays and lesbians should not be passed, because nobody else is harmed and nobody&amp;rsquo;s rights are violated, so the government should entirely get out of this business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Redistribution of Income from Rich to Poor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The libertarian think redistribution is a kind of coercion. What it amounts to is theft by the state or by the majority, if we&amp;rsquo;re talking about a
democracy, from people who happen to do very well and earn a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nozicks-argument-against-taxation&#34;&gt;Nozick&amp;rsquo;s Argument Against Taxation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxation = taking of earnings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking of earnings = forced labour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forced Labour = slavery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violates Principle of Self Possession&lt;/p&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/5-free-to-choose/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note|How to Measure Pleasure</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/4-how-to-measure-pleasure/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:38:44 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/4-how-to-measure-pleasure/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/4-how-to-measure-pleasure/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;objections-to-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;Objections to Utilitarianism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fails to respect individual rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not possible to aggregate all values and preferences
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a single measure like $$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t there a distinction between  higher and lower pleasure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The quantity of pleasure being equal, pushpin is as good as poetry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;Jeremy Bentham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it right to refuse to make qualitative distinctions? Can we dispense with the idea that certain things we take pleasure in are better or worthier than others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;j-s-mills-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;J. S. Mill&amp;rsquo;s Utilitarianism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/78/Stuart_Mill_G_F_Watts.jpg/300px-Stuart_Mill_G_F_Watts.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Stuart Mill&lt;/strong&gt; (20 May 1806 – 7 May 1873), usually cited as J. S. Mill, was an English philosopher, political economist, Member of Parliament, and civil servant.  He was a proponent of utilitarianism, an ethical theory developed by his predecessor Jeremy Bentham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mills-modification&#34;&gt;Mill&amp;rsquo;s Modification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;J. S. Mill tried to humanize utilitarianism. He tried to see whether the utilitarian calculus could be enlarged and modified to accommodate humanitarian concerns, like &lt;strong&gt;the concern to respect individual rights&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;to address the distinction between higher and lower pleasures&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;higher-and-lower-pleasures&#34;&gt;Higher and Lower Pleasures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher and lower pleasures are distinct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Of two pleasures, if there be one to which all or almost all who have experience of both give a decided preference, irrespective of any feeling of moral obligation to prefer it, then that is the more desirable pleasure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;John Stuart Mill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher pleasures require cultivation, appreciation, and education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once people are cultivated, they prefer the higher pleasures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is better to be a human being dissatisfied than a pig satisfied. Better to be Socrates dissatisfied than a fool satisfied. And if the fool or the pig are of a different opinion, it is because they only know their side of the question.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;John Stuart Mill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-individual-rights&#34;&gt;About Individual Rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;While I dispute the pretensions of any theory which sets up an imaginary standard of justice not grounded on utility, I account the justice which is grounded in utility to be the chief part, and incomparably the most sacred and binding part, of all morality&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;John Stuart Mill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Justice is a name, for certain moral requirements, which, regarded collectively, stand higher in the scale of social utility and are, therefore, of more paramount obligation than any others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;John Stuart Mill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice is not something that can easily be traded off against lesser things. But the reason in it is ultimately a utilitarian reason. Once you consider the long-run interests of humankind, of all of us as progressive beings. If we do justice and if we respect rights, &lt;strong&gt;society as a whole will be better off in the long run&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/4-how-to-measure-pleasure/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note|Putting A Price Tag on Life</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:07:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;phillip-morris-study&#34;&gt;Phillip Morris Study&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Cost/Benefit Analysis Smoking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philip Morris, the tobacco company, does huge business in the Czech Republic. They commissioned a cost-benefit analysis of smoking in the Czech Republic and found that the government allowing smoking could save money over the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zhengjian-l.github.io/images/phillip_morris_study.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ford-pinto-case&#34;&gt;The Ford Pinto Case&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was in the 1970s. The Ford Pinto, a kind of car, had a problem, which is that the fuel tank was at the back of the car and in rear collisions, the fuel tank exploded and some people were killed and some severely injured. Victims of these injuries took Ford to court to sue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the court case, they found that Ford had long since known about the problem and had done a cost-benefit analysis to determine whether it would be worth it to put in a special shield that would protect the fuel tank  and prevent it from exploding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zhengjian-l.github.io/images/repairing_the_ford_pinto.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposition-to-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;Proposition to utilitarianism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There needs to be a number on human life because we need to make decisions somehow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for the general, for the greater good. Someone has to be traded off for the sake of utility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;opposition-to-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;Opposition to utilitarianism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value to human life could not be assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It failed to take account things on suffering and emotional losses of the victims&#39; families.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does not consider the effect on the minority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zhengjian-l.github.io/images/Objections_to_utilitarianism.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;thorndikes-study&#34;&gt;Thorndike&amp;rsquo;s Study&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is possible to aggregate all values to translate them into dollar terms?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1930s, Thorndike tried to prove what utilitarianism assumes, that it is possible to translate all goods, all values, into a single uniform measure, and he conducted a survey of young recipients of relief. He gave them a list of unpleasant experiences and asked them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much would you have to be paid to undergo the following experiences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zhengjian-l.github.io/images/thorndike.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conclusion of the study:&lt;/strong&gt; Any want or a satisfaction which exists in some amount and is therefore measurable.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note|The Case of Cannibalism</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:20:15 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-benthamite-utilitarianism&#34;&gt;The Benthamite Utilitarianism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nature has placed mankind under the governance of two sovereign masters, pain and pleasure.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Jeremy Bentham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a lot of morally intuitive appeal, Bentham&amp;rsquo;s idea is the following, &lt;strong&gt;the right thing to do; the just thing to do is to maximize utility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The greatest good for the greatest number.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-queen-v-dudley-and-stephens-1984-the-lifeboat-case&#34;&gt;The Queen v. Dudley and Stephens (1984) (The Lifeboat Case)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XJ-fpulTiFg/VhqckUAmUvI/AAAAAAAACCg/RZxa06vCkf4/s1600/16051_383500421735417_439492146_n135.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A brief overview of the case:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Suppose you find yourself in a situation in which killing an innocent person is the only way to prevent many innocent people from dying. What’s the right thing to do? This question arose in The Queen v. Dudley and Stephens (1884), a famous English law case involving four men stranded in a lifeboat without food or water. How should we judge the action of Dudley and Stephens? Was it morally justified or morally wrong?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-defense-it-was-morally-justified&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The defense&lt;/strong&gt; (It was morally justified)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There had no choice. You have to do what you have to do to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Dudley and Stevens had asked Richard Parker&amp;rsquo;s for his consent, it was morally justified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dudley and Stevens had family. They survived, therefore, the greatest utility is created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prosecution-it-was-morally-wrong&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The prosecution&lt;/strong&gt; (It was morally wrong)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking others&#39; fate or lives in your own hands is no allowed under any circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the consent of Parker would not justify their killing him, because cannibalism itself is immoral and is a way of not valuing others&#39; lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not difference between lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions-raised&#34;&gt;Questions Raised&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we have certain fundamental rights?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does a fair procedure justify any result?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the moral work of consent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Note|The Moral Side of Murder</title>
        <link>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/</guid>
        <description>Zhengjian&#39;s Blog https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;trolley-problem&#34;&gt;Trolley Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;trolley problem&lt;/em&gt; is a thought experiment in ethics about a fictional scenario in which an onlooker has the choice to save 5 people in danger of being hit by a trolley, by diverting the trolley to kill just 1 person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you choose, to divert it or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;moral-reasoning&#34;&gt;Moral Reasoning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consequentialist-结果主义&#34;&gt;Consequentialist 结果主义&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequentialist locates morality in the consequences of an act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most influential example: &lt;strong&gt;Utilitarianism&lt;/strong&gt; (a doctrine invented by &lt;strong&gt;Jeremy Bentham&lt;/strong&gt;) 功利主义 边沁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;categorial-绝对主义&#34;&gt;Categorial 绝对主义&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Categorical locates morality in certain duties and rights. The most important philosopher of categorical moral reasoning German philosopher &lt;strong&gt;Immanuel Kant&lt;/strong&gt;(康德).&lt;/p&gt;
- https://zhengjian-l.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/ - This is a customized copyright.</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 