<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Note on Zhengjian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/tags/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Note on Zhengjian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is a customized copyright.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:07:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/tags/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Putting A Price Tag on Life</title>
      <link>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:07:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/3-putting-a-price-tag-on-life/</guid>
      <description>Phillip Morris Study (Cost/Benefit Analysis Smoking)
Philip Morris, the tobacco company, does huge business in the Czech Republic. They commissioned a cost-benefit analysis of smoking in the Czech Republic and found that the government allowing smoking could save money over the cost.
The Ford Pinto Case It was in the 1970s. The Ford Pinto, a kind of car, had a problem, which is that the fuel tank was at the back of the car and in rear collisions, the fuel tank exploded and some people were killed and some severely injured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case of Cannibalism</title>
      <link>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:20:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/2-the-case-of-cannibalism/</guid>
      <description>The Benthamite Utilitarianism  &amp;ldquo;Nature has placed mankind under the governance of two sovereign masters, pain and pleasure.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Jeremy Bentham
 With a lot of morally intuitive appeal, Bentham&amp;rsquo;s idea is the following, the right thing to do; the just thing to do is to maximize utility.
 &amp;ldquo;The greatest good for the greatest number.&amp;rdquo;
 The Queen v. Dudley and Stephens (1984) (The Lifeboat Case) A brief overview of the case: Suppose you find yourself in a situation in which killing an innocent person is the only way to prevent many innocent people from dying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Moral Side of Murder</title>
      <link>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Zhengjian-L.github.io/posts/justice/1-the-moral-side-of-murder/</guid>
      <description>Trolley Problem The trolley problem is a thought experiment in ethics about a fictional scenario in which an onlooker has the choice to save 5 people in danger of being hit by a trolley, by diverting the trolley to kill just 1 person.
What would you choose, to divert it or not?
Moral Reasoning   Consequentialist 结果主义   Consequentialist locates morality in the consequences of an act.
The most influential example: Utilitarianism (a doctrine invented by Jeremy Bentham) 功利主义 边沁</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
